# **Anthony Munene**

# **Frontend Developer**

• Email: munene.anthony@gmail.com

# **Profile**

Developer based in London with over 12 years of development experience. I am passionate and enthusiastic about what i do and the impact through code, that enables organisations to become more effective in delivering solutions to their client's problems.

Over the years developing, I've moulded myself into a well-rounded individual who appreciates best practice and progressively keeps up with new web technologies.

# **Skills**

- JavaScript
  - React
  - React Native
  - Node
  - o Jasmine, Karma, Enzyme, Jest
  - o Typescript
- HTML
  - Standards compliant, including WCAG 1.0 AA and WAI-ARIA
- CSS3
  - o PostCSS, SASS, LESS
  - Experience developing large-scale UI toolkit from scratch
- Devops/CI/CD
  - o AWS
  - Docker
  - Jenkins
  - Gitlab
- DB
  - o MongoDB
  - MySQL
  - Redis
  - o Postgres

# **Professional History**

#### **Equal Experts**

August 2015 - Current Worked for clients listed below:

• Klarna (Tel Aviv / Berlin)

February 2018 - December 2018

- Support and develop the authentication feature for the Klarna mobile application built in React Native
- o Support and develop the UI for Klarna's checkout service using React
- Support and develop features for the Klarna authentication service built using Express and Redis.

**Stack:** JavaScript (Express, Node, React, React Native, Jest, Jasmine), Docker, AWS, Jenkins, Ruby, Redis

#### • Tesco groceries

July 2016 - March 2018

Worked as part of a team tasked with delivering a full revamp of the Tesco groceries website Developed an internal tool that allowed Tesco to integrate Adobe's experiment platform in order to carry out A/B testing **Stack:** JavaScript (React, Express, Node), HTML, CSS

#### • **UXForms**

May 2016 - July 2016

Worked solely as the frontend developer tasked with building the UXforms website and creating styles of the UXForms templates

Stack: JavaScript (Jquery), HTML, CSS

## Mergermarket(Acuris)

September 2015 - May 2016

Frontend role split between working with UX to create prototypes for Mergermarket's internal mobile app and working with the main development team to integrate the chose designs.

### HM Revenue & Customs

August 2013 - August 2015 Using the standard look and feel set by the government digital service to develop and provide a frontend toolkit that would allow government services to build/prototype applications with minimal hassle.

Stack: JavaScript (Jquery), HTML, CSS

# **Education**

**Buckinghamshire University, High Wycombe** 

Bachelor of Technology Degree (2005 - 2008)